# **AIMAN EQBAL**

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Bengaluru, India | 1aimaneqbal@gmail.com | +91-7277384783 | linkedin.com/in/aiman-eqbal

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Creative, people-oriented and well versed in the field of Computer Applications with project development and management experience. Having 2.5 years of experience in designing developing, and implementing software solutions. Team player with excellent communication skills, high quality of work, driven and highly self-motivated. Strong analysis skills and able to work independently as well as with big teams.

#### **AREA OF EXPERTISE**

✓ Java	✓ C++	✓ React.js	✓ SQL
✓ Express.js	✓ C	✓ JavaScript	✓ MongoDB
✓ Node.js	✓ CSS	✓ Python	✓ Spring Boot

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### Staff Consultant, CEMLI Developer @ Oracle | September 2024 – Present

Got promoted within 2 years by maintaining more than 90% performance rating in the previous 2-year performance review. Some of the responsibilities that entailed:

- Developed multiple new features as a part of enhancement of Oracle Banking Payments (OBPM) product of Oracle Banking Suite
- Developed and delivered a full-stack customization for a requirement related to Demand Draft and Bankers Cheque
- Created numerous microservices for integration between two payment product processors.
- Managed and trained 2 junior consultants and 2 interns while leading UAT development support for ongoing project.

#### Associate Consultant, CEMLI Developer @ Oracle | July 2022 – August 2024

Joined Oracle as fresher as an Associate Consultant. During this period working as a CEMLI developer for one of the biggest banks in UAE in an upgrade project, some of the responsibilities that entailed:

- Helped in setting up a completely new domestic payments network, similar to IMPS/RTGS money transfer.
- Customized a new network for instant payments similar to UPI to process transactions within 300 milliseconds.
- Designed various front-end transaction screens using React.JS.
- Created new environments on docker containers for deployment, unit testing and internal testing throughout the project.
- Supported the upgrade of OBPM product processor and helped in running patch-set upgrades.

### Software Developer Engineer, Intern @ Relecura | Jan 2022 – June 2022

Joined Relecura as an SDE Intern. During the course of this time I was asked to design, develop and deliver a completely new webapp which was supposed to track the internal usage of resources within the organization.

- Helped in processing the raw usage data to be used in the API services.
- Designed and Developed the UI from scratch using React.js
- Integrated live statistical data from Google Cloud Platform into the web-app.
- Integrated "Cognito", a secure login service by AWS into the web-app.
- Successfully pitched the idea of using the web-app by the sales team during acquiring new clients by presenting the usefulness of resource usage by other clients.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Application – Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra | Class of 2019-2022 | 9.27 GPA Bachelor of Computer Application – Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra | Class of 2016-2019 | 8.11 GPA

#### **TECHNICAL AND FUNCTIONAL SKILLS**

Data Structures and Algorithms, ReST API, MVC, MVVM, Docker, Database, PL/SQL, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Three.js, Jira, Git, Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, VS Code, IntelliJ Idea.